<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on James Martin</title>
    <link>https://example.com/projects/creations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on James Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/projects/creations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inverse Distance Weighting</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/creations/idw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/creations/idw/</guid>
      <description>A common geostatstical technique used to interpolate values across a study area based on a number of explicit sample locations. I had trouble finding a package in the R repository that implemented this technique in a simple way which proved to be a problem when using IDW to interpolate air pollution concentrations at millions of locations. To make it computationally feasible I coded IDW and an accuracy metric as c++ functions and included them in a package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Accessibility Models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/creations/access/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/creations/access/</guid>
      <description>Health accessibility models have been used to identify regions that are medically under-served due to their population and distance from medical facilities. I used these models to identify neighborhoods in the city of Huaquillas that may lack access to vector control services. I also simulate how different placements of workers and resources could improve access and identify locations to optimally place a new facility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFMathGeo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/creations/ufmethgeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/creations/ufmethgeo/</guid>
      <description>UFMathGeo is a mechanistic model used to estimate the probability of finding two species of disease transmitting mosquito for a given month in a number of counties in the US. For archival purposes the code available on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Networks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/creations/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/creations/network/</guid>
      <description>There are many powerful R packages that allow users to perform network analyses. However there currently isn’t the build-in functionality to use these analyses on spatial datasets. To study a road network for example, you need to convert the shapefile GIS format into an object that is accepted by a package like ‘igraph’. I provide an example on how to perform these conversions and use network analysis to find the shortest route between two locations in the road network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
